Serena Lertkantitham

(425) 269-7921 **(a)** lertkantitham lertkantitham@gmail.com (a) slertka

Summary & Skills

Proactive engineer working in the medical device field transitioning to software development. A strategic thinker and skilled communicator with an innate ability to lead and manage relationships.

Front End: JavaScript, ES6, ReactJS/Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, RESTful APIs, Responsive Design Back End: NodeJS, NoSQL: Mongoose/MongoDB, Mocha, Chai, Unit Level Testing Other: Collaborative, Project Management, Strong Problem Solving, Interpersonal

Recent Projects

PLEX - Connecting Yogis: A full-stack application connecting yoga instructors and yoga studios to find open classes to teach. Built with React, Node, Express, MongoDB, JavaScript, HTML/CSS.

Weekly: An application to build an open-dated weekly planner to track upcoming events and tasks. Built with Node.js, Express, Passport, MongoDB, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS.

1hike2beer: Utilized Google Maps JavaScript API and REI's Hiking Project API to provide a tailored geographical search experience for the user. Built with JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS.

Education and Credentials

Thinkful, Continued Education

Dec 2018 – Aug 2019

- Proactively pursued full-stack web development bootcamp to pursue passion for coding and to achieve future career goals of transitioning to software engineering
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while demonstrating proficiency in JavaScript and its frameworks by collaborating 20+ hours a week with a senior web developer

Santa Clara University

Sep 2010 – Jun 2014

- Bachelor of Science in Biomedical Engineering
- Minor in Math (emphasis in statistics)
- First Generation Scholar; Clare Boothe Luce Scholar; Order of the Engineer Inductee

Professional Experience

Boston Scientific

Aug 2016 – Present

Supplier Engineer II

- Initiate and coordinate multiple strategic value improvement projects at high-risk suppliers to deliver \$500K+ year-over-year savings on global commodity spend
- Investigate and evaluate supplier- and material-related changes for new and sustaining projects
- Yielded \$150k cash savings annually by increasing efficiencies of the group and leveraging existing data between supplier final inspection and internal incoming inspection
- Earned achievements: 2017 Quality Award Winner, 2018 Value Improvement Project Award

All Sensors Corporation

Dec 2014 - Jul 2016

Quality Engineer

- Redesigned boiler-plate inspections that led to a 75% reduction in processing time of returns from initial customer request to failure analysis report and disposition
- Closed 90% of open CAPAs, SCARs, and audits within first year of on-boarding